Social History of Spencer, Indiana 1974-1975 ohrc092
Center for Documentary Research and Practice
- Parrish, Arthur, October 12, 1974; 74-009; Perry, Robert; 15 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 40 minutes; no index
  Arthur Parrish was born October 2, 1915, and died November 1977 in Spencer, Indiana. He talks about growing up on a farm in the country and attending a one-room school. He speaks of living through the Great Depression. He talks about the changes he has observed in Spencer over the years, and compares his way of life as a youth to the youth of today.
  child discipline; farming methods; funeral services; Great Depression; one-room schools; religious beliefs
- Propes, Marcy and Robert (Bob), February 20, 1975; 75-045; Perry, Bob; 1 open reel tape, 76 minutes, no index
  Scope Note
  Robert and Marcy Propes, born before the Second World War, speak about the welcoming small town community in Spencer, Indiana. Both speak about the stable economy, the close-knit community, and educational opportunities in Spencer that made it a great place to raise a family. Robert discusses his time as a school board member. He speaks about the conservative nature of the town, its reaction to African-American families moving in to the community, and the construction of new homes.
  Spencer, Indiana; Indianapolis (Ind.); Prospect Park (Ind.); African Americans; Catholic church; Chamber of Commerce; community; education philosophy; high school; high school basketball; high school education; high school football; primary education; Race relations; school board
- Ramsey, Stella, November 7, 1974; 74-002; Hatfield, David; 23 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 55 minutes; no index
  Stella Ramsey was born November 18, 1894, and died January 1984. She talks about the changes she has observed in Owen County over the years. She speaks of her religious beliefs and her involvement in an Assembly of God Church in Spencer, Indiana. She discusses the moral decay of society, which she feels is due to low church attendance and lack of belief of God.
  church pianist; Assembly of God church; charismatic Christian movement; child discipline; Christian crusade; Communism; economic class differences; funeral services; Great Depression; one-room schools; patriotism; Poetry; racial discrimination; religious beliefs; separation of church and state; small town life; Scott, Derby
- Reed, Ron, December 1975; 75-056; Fenton, Leslie; 18 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 45 minutes; no index
  Ron Reed, part owner of the Tivoli Theater in Spencer, Indiana, shares his observations of small town life. He talks about the political and economic situation in the town. He talks about the disparate economic classes in Spencer. Finally, he discusses the history of the Tivoli Theater and his future plans for the business.
  small business owner; San Diego, California; community development; economic class differences; local politics; small town life; San Diego State College; Spencer Chamber of Commerce; Tivoli Theater
- Royer, Ernest; Royer, Gladys, October 14, 1974; 74-020; Noland, Craig; Perry, Robert; 61 pages; 2 tapes, 1 3/4 ips, 145 minutes; no index
  Ernest and Gladys Royer have lived in Spencer, Indiana for many years. They talk about the 1920s and 1930s and the changes in transportation, social life, and town atmosphere that have taken place since then. They speak of their involvement in the local Presbyterian church and the people they have known throughout their lives.
  Bloomington, Indiana; Patricksburg, Indiana; Stinesville, Indiana; bank robbery; church attendance; circuses; county founders; funeral services; Indianapolis 500; local fires; local history; local scandal; Presbyterian Church; Prohibition; religious beliefs; retirement; town band; Farm Life; Indiana University; Tivoli Theater; Anderson, Carl, 1875-1943; Scott, Derby
- Sartin, Reverend (Rev.), November 14, 1974; 74-024; Nolan, Craig; No transcript, 2 tapes, 3 3/4 ips, 76 mintues, no index
  Reverend Sartin, born August 27, 1927, discusses the important role religion should have on the individual, family, and schooling. Reverend Sartin also discusses the closeness and sense of community in Spencer, Indiana. He briefly discusses intergernational differences of opportunity and ambition.
  Spencer, Indiana; Christianity; citizenship; church influence; community; close-knit community; discipline; generational differences; Mississippi; Nashville, Tennessee; Religion; religion and family; small town life
- Sharp, William and Elizabeth, January 22, 1975; 75-047; Crouch, Tamara; Hatfield, David; Noland, Craig; 31 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 75 minutes; no index
  Judge William Sharp and his wife Elizabeth have lived in Spencer, Indiana for the past six years. They describe the differences in small town life in Spencer and life in Indianapolis, Indiana. They talk about local politics and a local scandal involving the school board. Finally, Judge Sharp discusses his duties as the county judge, and his interactions with the Owen County Welfare Board.
  judge; Indianapolis, Indiana; church attendance; community development; economic class differences; local politics; local religious communities; local scandal; school consolidation; small town life; Owen County Welfare Board; Owen Valley High School
- Smith, Mary Frances, October 17, 1974; 74-003; Noland, Craig; 30 pages; 1 tape. 3 3/4 ips, 70 minutes; no index
  Mary Frances Smith, born December 15, 1898 and died May 1981, lived in Spencer, Indiana most of her life. She discusses the differences in Spencer when she was young and Spencer today. She speaks of the general decline in morality, citizenship, and decency over the years, which she feels is mostly due to a decrease in church attendance, irresponsible parenting, and women working outside the home. She also talks about memories she has of growing up in Spencer.
  Indianapolis, Indiana; bank robbery; child discipline; church activities; Great Depression; missionary work; poverty; Presbyterian Church; religious beliefs; small town life
- Spangler, Renos, October 10, 1974; 74-002; Hatfield, David; 19 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 45 minutes; no index
  Renos Spangler, born November 11, 1902 and died January 4, 1992, lived in Owen County his whole life. He discusses the many changes that have taken place over time in Spencer, Indiana, including changes in child discipline, religious beliefs and church attendance, economic factors, education, and small town life in general. He also relates some memories of events and people in Spencer.
  teacher; Patricksburg, Indiana; child discipline; local religious communities; Lutheran church; Prohibition; small town life
- Stewart, Betty R. and Frank, January 30, 1975; 75-050; Hatfield, David; Noland, Craig; Perry, Robert; Not transcribed; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 55 minutes; no index
  Frank and Betty R. Stewart talk about the local history of Spencer, Indiana, compare small town life in Spencer to life in a big city, discuss the religious communities active in Spencer, and talk about discipline in public schools.
  child discipline; local history; local religious communities; small town life
- Stogsdill, Dan, June 17, 1975; 75-071; Brown, Mike; Not transcribed; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 35 minutes; no index
  Dan Stogsdill talks about the local history of Spencer, Indiana, including local politics, the shift of community social functions from the church to the school, and the problem of finding work in Spencer, leading young people to move out of the community.
  community changes; employment; local history; local politics; societal changes
- Sturgell, Lela Mae, June 12, 1975; 75-061; Brown, Mike; Not transcribed; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 35 minutes; no index
  Lela Mae Sturgell discusses local history and politics and small town life in Spencer, Indiana. She also discusses her religious beliefs and compares today's educational methods with those from her schooling.
  local history; local politics; religious beliefs; small town life; teaching methods
- Walker, Jon, December, 1975; 75-065; Brown, Mike; 11 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 25 minutes; no index
  Jon Walker has lived in Spencer, Indiana for the past four years. He speaks of the history of the town, especially the Tivoli Theater, of which he is part owner. He talks about his activities on the Spencer Chamber of Commerce. He also discusses how an increase in the tourist trade could potentially help Spencer become a more prosperous community.
  small business owner; local history; tourism industry; Spencer Chamber of Commerce; Tivoli Theater
- Wardlaw, Janet, November 30, 1974; 75-008; Brown, Mike; Perry, Robert; Not transcribed; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 110 minutes; no index
  Janet Wardlaw discusses the history of Spencer, Indiana and the religious communities that are active there.
  local history; local religious communities
- Wardlaw, John, December 5, 1974; 75-010; Noland, Craig; 29 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 70 minutes; no index
  John Wardlaw has lived in Spencer, Indiana for the past two years. He speaks of the advantages and disadvantages of small town life. He talks about the initial reluctance of the community to accept his family. He discusses the dynamics among Spencer's religious communities. He talks about the conservative nature of the school system and the steps that need to be taken to make it more progressive.
  child discipline; community development; economic class differences; local politics; local religious communities; local scandal; religious beliefs; small town life; teaching methods
- Wesley, T. Perry, October 3 ,1974; 74-007; Noland, Craig; 29 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 70 minutes; no index
  T. Perry Wesley has lived in Spencer, Indiana for the past thirty years. He originally came to Spencer to purchase and run the local newspaper, which he managed until his retirement. Mr. Wesley compares small town life in Spencer to other communities he has lived in. He talks about Spencer's religious communities and how they interact with each other. Finally, he discusses his own religious and moral beliefs.
  journalist; newspaper owner; Indianapolis, Indiana; economic class differences; local religious communities; Prohibition; religious beliefs; separation of church and state; small town life
- Whitaker, Richard, October, 1975; 75-076; Brown, Mike; 16 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 40 minutes; no index
  Richard Whitaker discusses the infiltration of Communists in the United States Government, the disintegration of moral responsibility, and his opposition to the Equal Rights Amendment.
  Communism; Equal Rights Amendment; local politics; national politics; religious beliefs
- White, Cecil, November 1, 1975; 75-078; Noland, Craig; Perry, Robert; 23 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 55 minutes; no index
  Cecil White was born September 27, 1910 and died January 30, 1989. He talks about the small Spencer, Indiana school he attended through the sixth grade and the subjects he studied. He speaks of the changes he has observed in Spencer since his childhood. He speaks of his religious beliefs and the importance of the Pentecostal church he attends in Spencer. He also shares some memories of Spencer through the years.
  Spencer, Indiana; child discipline; Great Depression; local religious communities; Pentecostal church; religious beliefs; school consolidation; separation of church and state; small town life; Scott, Derby
- White, Glendora, October 26, 1974; 74-021; Brown, Mike; 41 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 35 minutes; no index
  Glendora White has lived in Owen County her whole life. She discusses the school she attended as a child. She talks about growing up on a farm, and the changes that have occurred in farming methods over the years. She shares stories of her ancestors and of Spencer in general. She talks about small town life in Spencer and how it has changed. She also discusses her religious beliefs and the importance of the Christian church in her life.
  Freedom, Indiana; bank robbery; farming methods; Great Depression; murder; religious beliefs; small town life; Women's Christian Fellowship
- Williams, Rosa, June 17, 1975; 75-059; Brown, Mike; 9 pages; 1 tape, 3 3/4 ips, 25 minutes; no index
  Rosa Williams, born in 1897, spent most of her life in Spencer, Indiana. She discusses education, religion, family, the community, and how they have all changed over the years. She also discusses the Great Depression and how it effected her family and the community.
  church; community changes; Education; family; farming; Great Depression
- Wimberly, William, November 14, 1974; 75-009; Hatfield, David; Lucas, Paul; Noland, Craig; Not transcribed; 1 reel, 3 3/4 ips; 50 minutes
  Restricted: Contact center staff for more information
  William Wimberly, born in 1938, discusses his life in Spencer, Indiana. He covers topics such as religion, education, and community life.
  Owen County, Indiana; community education; community life; religious beliefs
- Yockey, Virginia, January 1975; 75-007; Brown, Mike; Crouch, Tamara; 35 pages; 1 reel, 3 3/4 ips, 80 minutes; no index
  Virginia Yockey discusses her life in Spencer, Indiana. She discusses changes in the community, education, activities, and child rearing. Mrs. Yockey describes community activities and the advantages of living in a small town. She discusses the town's civic pride and the importance of patriotism.
  Illinois; Indianapolis, Indiana; Owen County, Indiana; child discipline; child-rearing; civic pride; community activities; generation gap; household budgeting; patriotism; religious beliefs; small town advantages; Indiana University; Jackson, Margaret